我去了全国白人比率最高的缅因州。
I went to Maine, the whitest state in the nation,
也是人口老化最严重的州，
the oldest,
每年的死亡人口比出生人口还多。
where there are more deaths every year than births,
我去了刘易斯顿市， 一个正在凋零的工业城，
and I went to this dying mill town called Lewiston
因为新来人口而焕发了生机——
that is being revitalized by new people --
大部分是黑人和穆斯林，
mostly African, mostly Muslim,
还有一些外国移民和难民。
immigrants and refugees.
在那儿，我遇见了一位女士， 名叫塞西尔，
There, I met a woman named Cecile,
她的父母是最后一波
whose parents had been part of the last wave of new people
搬到刘易斯顿市的新移民。
to come to Lewiston.
他们是世纪之初来到这里的 法裔加拿大工人。
These are French-Canadian millworkers at the turn of the century.
虽然塞西尔退休了， 但她找到了新的人生目标。
Cecile is retired, but she had found a new purpose in life,